<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on D00k</title>
    <link>https://d00k.net/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on D00k</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ie</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 21:39:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d00k.net/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rebble Weather Icons</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/rebble_weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 16:23:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/rebble_weather/</guid>
      <description>The task  Inspired by the Pebble revival project, Rebble and their unique aesthetic inspired by the original series of icons developed by Heydays design for pebble, I set out to make my own weather icons to use in projects on the watches in the future. While I took inspiration to make them familiar to users, I also sought to give them their own flair and personality.
  The original Pebble icons, designed by Heydays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>adwaitapod</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/adwaitapod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 14:45:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/adwaitapod/</guid>
      <description>Adwaitapod is a modern and feature-rich theme for iPod Video models running Rockbox. The theme uses the principles of Gnome&amp;rsquo;s Adwaita design language, and aims to be a complete and pleasing experience for users.   The music player screen.   
Features ∘ Consistent interface with rounded corners. ∘ Custom Lockscreen when the Hold switch is on in the main menu, or when USB is connected. ∘ Radio Player skin with station icon support when using an FM Presets file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streetwalker</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/streetwalker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 18:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/streetwalker/</guid>
      <description>Streetwalker was a project started in 2016 in an attempt to learn lua and the pico-8 virtual console. After experiencing Graphics Exercise by Mason Lindroth, I was inspired to create my own walking sim with the goal of filling the system&amp;rsquo;s 1024x512 pixel map space.
     The game&amp;rsquo;s design takes heavy inspiration from digital maps as well as the brutalist architecture movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Gallery</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/virtual-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 18:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/virtual-gallery/</guid>
      <description>The Virtual Gallery a website was born in the summer of 2020 after the cancellation of an exhibition that an art course I was attending hosted. Not wanting the work and effort of everyone I did the course with to go to waste, I set out to make a platform for them to share with their friends and family.
The Exhibition      Work took several months to build a basic site from scratch using HTML and CSS, largely due to my inexperience however I learned a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origami Designs</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/origami-designs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 18:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/origami-designs/</guid>
      <description>Origami Modular Festive Tree      The Origami festive tree is a modular origami tree with little slots in the leaves to put whatever you want! It was designed as a modular, flat-packable festive tree that could be practical, allowing you to put different decorations or items in it. The design still needs some tweaking before I&amp;rsquo;m happy with posting instructions, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably get around to it soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gamejams</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/gamejams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 12:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/gamejams/</guid>
      <description>Tiny-TV Jam       Tiny-TV Jam ran for a week in January 2017. The goal of the jam was to make a small game that fit within the 10x11 resolution of the TV in the pico-8 cart provided. I entered the jam almost by accident, having no programming knowledge, I had messed around with the cart and designed a detailed recreation of a Macintosh 128k pc. I decided to make a game, Tiny Cookie Clicker, and the jam provided some great design challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Famicase Exhibition</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/famicase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/famicase/</guid>
      <description>The Famicase Exhibition is an annual exhibition hosted by the Super Meteor store located in Tokyo, Japan. Entry is open to anyone worldwide, and the goal is create a cover for a fictional Famicom game of your creation.
Famicase Exhibition 2021 entry - Become       The 2021 Famicase Exhibition took place between April 29th and May 31st.
 ⬩ Famicase Website.   ⬩ Purchase the Famicase 2021 Zine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
