<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux Wiki on D00k</title>
    <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux Wiki on D00k</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ie</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 21:13:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d00k.net/knowledge/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PDF Utilities</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/linux/pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 21:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/linux/pdf/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s been plenty of times I&amp;rsquo;ve had to work on PDFs, be it taking out certain pages to sign and adding them back, or even creating PDFs from scratch with images. Common advice would direct you to websites online with loads of different tools for this, but privacy concerns combined with having to wait for uploads and so on make them pretty inconvenient. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a couple of command line tools which make working with PDFs almost painless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SFTP &amp; SSH</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/linux/sftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 18:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/linux/sftp/</guid>
      <description>SFTP, or the SSH File Transfer Protocol, is a tool for transferring files between systems and is an extension of the SSH protocol. SFTP gives you access to the terminal of both the machine you are using, as well as the system you are connecting to, at the same time.
SSH  SSH, or the Secure Shell Protocol, is a method of connecting to the terminal of another system. Without it, we cannot use SFTP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImageMagick</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/linux/imagemagick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 22:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/linux/imagemagick/</guid>
      <description>The ImageMagick suite is a widely useful collection of commands for editing, modifying and converting images. When converting large amounts of images it really comes into it&amp;rsquo;s own, you can easily convert entire directories of images in a single command. I use ImageMagick for many things, mainly though for optimising images here on the website.
Mogrify vs Convert  Most of what we&amp;rsquo;ll be looking at will be using the Mogrify command, however there are other ImageMagick commands, the most relevant to use here being the Convert command.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
