<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on D00k</title>
    <link>https://d00k.net/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on D00k</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ie</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 16:23:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d00k.net/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rebble Weather Icons</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/rebble_weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 16:23:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/rebble_weather/</guid>
      <description>The task  The Pebble revival project, Rebble, has been branching out to make replacement apps and firmware for Pebbles to help with longevity. Part of this has included remaking icons as the original Pebble ones are not open source or legally usable. This page details the weather icons I designed for the project, and for use in my own watchfaces. They follow the same rules as the original icons, however have their own Rebble twist to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>adwaitapod</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/adwaitapod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 14:45:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/adwaitapod/</guid>
      <description>Adwaitapod is a modern and feature-rich theme for iPod Video models running Rockbox. The theme uses the principles of Gnome&amp;rsquo;s Adwaita design language, and aims to be a complete and pleasing experience for users.   The music player screen.   
Features ∘ Consistent interface with rounded corners. ∘ Custom Lockscreen when the Hold switch is on in the main menu, or when USB is connected. ∘ Radio Player skin with station icon support when using an FM Presets file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colophon</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/about/colophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 19:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/about/colophon/</guid>
      <description>A comprehensive dive into the design, creation and philosophy of this site.
Site Philosophy  This site exists to scratch an itch I&amp;rsquo;ve long had. Sharing stuff on social media has never been my mojo, I&amp;rsquo;ll often post my photography, however I yearned for something more expansive and interesting, so I made a website.
 The design of this site was made with one goal in mind: create vibrant a site that looks good and is fun to use, with the smallest file size possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Gallery</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/virtual-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 18:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/virtual-gallery/</guid>
      <description>The Virtual Gallery a website was born in the summer of 2020 after the cancellation of an exhibition that an art course I was attending hosted. Not wanting the work and effort of everyone I did the course with to go to waste, I set out to make a platform for them to share with their friends and family.
The Exhibition      Work took several months to build a basic site from scratch using HTML and CSS, largely due to my inexperience however I learned a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origami Designs</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/origami-designs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 18:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/origami-designs/</guid>
      <description>Origami Modular Festive Tree      The Origami festive tree is a modular origami tree with little slots in the leaves to put whatever you want! It was designed as a modular, flat-packable festive tree that could be practical, allowing you to put different decorations or items in it. The design still needs some tweaking before I&amp;rsquo;m happy with posting instructions, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably get around to it soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Famicase Exhibition</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/famicase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/famicase/</guid>
      <description>The Famicase Exhibition is an annual exhibition hosted by the Super Meteor store located in Tokyo, Japan. Entry is open to anyone worldwide, and the goal is create a cover for a fictional Famicom game of your creation.
Famicase Exhibition 2021 entry - Become       The 2021 Famicase Exhibition took place between April 29th and May 31st.
 ⬩ Famicase Website.   ⬩ Purchase the Famicase 2021 Zine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
