<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wiki on d00k</title>
    <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wiki on d00k</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ie</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 23:27:59 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://d00k.net/wiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vector_graphics</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/rockbox_advanced/vector_graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 22:31:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/rockbox_advanced/vector_graphics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Rockbox themes, there is a missing link between re-colourable graphics and anti-aliased graphics. With all of the classical features, it is impossible to achieve an asset that exhibits both of these properties. However if we take advantage of the font system, we can created accurate vector graphics that behave exactly like images which are anti-aliased and can be re-coloured. This guide will go over my notes and explorations into this new practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Themed Lists Exploration Notes</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/rockbox_advanced/themed_lists_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:06:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/rockbox_advanced/themed_lists_notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some loose notes on the Rockbox Theme engine feature that allows you to theme the menu lists of the Ui. Mostly covering my own exploration and experimentation to achieve desired results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This feature is largely unexplored territory in terms of it&amp;rsquo;s potential. Only a very small handful of people have made themes from scratch with this feature, gevaerts who is a Rockbox developer and Frankenpod who is one of the most experienced creators of themes. Recently with adwaitapod 3.0, I utilised the feature to create the highly custom &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/D0-0K/adwaitapod/wiki/User-Preference-Settings&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;user preference settings menus&lt;/a&gt;, but this is as far as I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Missing Features List</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/rockbox_advanced/missing_features/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 17:12:08 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/rockbox_advanced/missing_features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page serves as documentation for my plans to extend the system which powers themes in Rockbox. This current plan aims to extend the abilities available to themes while following the intentions which the theme engine was built around.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;listbox box&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 style=&#34;padding:12px 5%;&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Menu&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#currently-working-on&#34; &gt;• &lt;span class=&#34;underline&#34;&gt;Currently Working On&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#planned-features&#34; &gt;• &lt;span class=&#34;underline&#34;&gt;Planned Features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#distant-plans&#34; &gt;• &lt;span class=&#34;underline&#34;&gt;Distant Plans&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;currently-working-on&#34;&gt;Currently Working On&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are features I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on programming within Rockbox&amp;rsquo;s source code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Image Compression Tests</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/web/images/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 13:50:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/web/images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;text borderless box&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;- Images must be smaller than the current ImageMagick script.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;- The maximum resolution must be 720x480.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;- Images must have colour to maintain readability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hypothesis&#34;&gt;Hypothesis&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two possible routes come to mind immediately. The first would be using a modern image format, likely webp for now, however this method would leave users on older browsers stuck with whatever alternative. The other route might actually provide a nice alternative, or be just as good on it&amp;rsquo;s own. Reducing the colours of an image, and using the gif image format. Since gifs are indexed, having less colours would mean smaller filesizes. However my previous tests with gifs didn&amp;rsquo;t give me too much hope in it&amp;rsquo;s ability to be small. The ultimate goal with these tests will be to come to some clear conclusions on various methods of making small images.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rockbox Image Optimisation</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/rockbox_advanced/rockbox_image_optimisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 17:20:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/rockbox_advanced/rockbox_image_optimisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When producing Rockbox themes with large feature-sets, images can quickly become a bottleneck both in terms of filesize as well as graphical quality. There are many ways to address these issues, however in this guide I will cover the best practices I have discovered and incorporated into my toolbox.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-bitmap-image-format&#34;&gt;The Bitmap image format&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rockbox&amp;rsquo;s primary image format is the Bitmap. Versions 3 and 4 of the bitmap spec are recognised, while any lower specs are not. The wiki &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rockbox.org/wiki/CustomWPS#LCD_Screen_Sizes_47_BMP_Compatibility&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;states&lt;/a&gt; that 1-bit, 24-bit and 32-bit Bitmaps are supported, however from experience 16-bit is also acceptable. I bring up 16-bits as all images used by Rockbox are converted into 16-bit colour regardless. This brings up the first issues. When this conversion is done, no dithering is applied, leaving an often unsavoury and harsh result. By pre-processing our images, we can not only achieve better looking results but also much smaller filesizes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PDF Utilities</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/linux/pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 21:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/linux/pdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s been plenty of times I&amp;rsquo;ve had to work on PDFs, be it taking out certain pages to sign and adding them back, or even creating PDFs from scratch with images. Common advice would direct you to websites online with loads of different tools for this, but privacy concerns combined with having to wait for uploads and so on make them pretty inconvenient. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a couple of command line tools which make working with PDFs almost painless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SFTP &amp; SSH</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/linux/sftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 18:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/linux/sftp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SFTP, or the SSH File Transfer Protocol, is a tool for transferring files between systems and is an extension of the SSH protocol. SFTP gives you access to the terminal of both the machine you are using, as well as the system you are connecting to, at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ssh&#34;&gt;SSH&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;SSH, or the Secure Shell Protocol, is a method of connecting to the terminal of another system. Without it, we cannot use SFTP. It needs to be set up and configured on both ends, however it&amp;rsquo;s not too difficult a process. The best guide I&amp;rsquo;ve found is homebrewserver.club&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://homebrewserver.club/demystifying-ssh.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demystifying SSH&lt;/a&gt; tutorial. Following it with zero experience, I was able to get SSH set up with no issues fairly quickly and highly recommend it if you&amp;rsquo;re also a beginner wanting to get into SSH.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ImageMagick Guide</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/linux/imagemagick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 22:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/linux/imagemagick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ImageMagick suite is a widely useful collection of commands for editing, modifying and converting images. When converting large amounts of images it really comes into it&amp;rsquo;s own, you can easily convert entire directories of images in a single command. I use ImageMagick for many things, mainly though for optimising images here on the website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;mogrify-vs-convert&#34;&gt;Mogrify vs Convert&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of what we&amp;rsquo;ll be looking at will be using the &lt;strong&gt;Mogrify&lt;/strong&gt; command, however there are other ImageMagick commands, the most relevant to use here being the &lt;strong&gt;Convert&lt;/strong&gt; command. For the most part, both commands do the same things however the way they do them differs. &lt;strong&gt;Mogrify&lt;/strong&gt; is pretty general and (most times) overwrites the targetted files, &lt;strong&gt;Convert&lt;/strong&gt; on the other hand creates a separate file which it outputs to. With &lt;strong&gt;Convert&lt;/strong&gt; we also have finer control over the output, allowing us to rename files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pico-8 Games List</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/pico8-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 19:19:54 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/pico8-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lexaloffle.com/pico-8.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pico-8&lt;/a&gt; is a fantasy console for playing and making smol games. There has been a vibrant community surrounding the system for years, and some fantastic games have been produced during that time. This list is a compiled collection of my personal favourites, and games I consider to be some of the best on the system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-wasters&#34;&gt;Time Wasters&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;These games a short and quick to play, but an absolute blast whenever you want to waste some time or just chill!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seed Harvesting</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/seedharvesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 11:05:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/seedharvesting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I have researched wild flowers and their benefits over hybrid seeds and plants found in garden centers. Part of this led me to harvesting seeds from my garden and planting them. I still have some flowers I harvested that I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to write up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;img class=&#34;highlight&#34; src=&#34;https://d00k.net/img/wiki/savingseeds02.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;Dried up bulbs on a flower stem&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bluebells&#34;&gt;Bluebells&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My first experiment in seed harvesting was with bluebells. In recent years we&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a large patch of wild bluebells, however due to the scale of the garden, they&amp;rsquo;d never naturally spread to some areas where I&amp;rsquo;d like them so I took a shot at gathering seeds from them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bee Encyclopedia</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/bees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 18:01:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/bees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ireland is home to 100 different bee species, with 78% being solitary bee species. This incredible amount of diversity that lives right under our noses fascinates me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve set out to photograph and record as many as I possibly can. As this encyclopedia progresses, I expect the need for it to be further categorised and sectioned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another thing to note is that I don&amp;rsquo;t believe my common bumble bee classifications to be correct, and am in the process of recording more photos to fix this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Font Combining</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/rockbox_advanced/font_combining/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 13:00:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/rockbox_advanced/font_combining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When making Rockbox themes, there are numerous built in fonts to choose from. However sometimes, these may not suit the theme you are building. In situations like these, users can make their own fonts. This guide goes over several ways people can achieve this, including a guide on combining two different fonts together to create a wider language supporting font.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-rockbox-fonts&#34;&gt;Making Rockbox Fonts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rockbox uses it&amp;rsquo;s own, custom font format for it&amp;rsquo;s interface. Therefore it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to convert our fonts for use in themes. This process is slightly different for colour and monochrome models, the former allowing anti-aliasing and the latter using exclusively bitmaps fonts. For the moment I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on the non-bitmap conversion process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reusing Technology</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/reusingtech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 18:13:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/reusingtech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-world-has-a-tech-waste-problem&#34;&gt;Our world has a tech waste problem&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s really no hiding the fact. Our world is built around fast fashion and fast tech, we buy and we throw out. Because of this, there&amp;rsquo;s loads of old, unused phones and other bits lying around the house that I&amp;rsquo;ve sought to utilise and solve problems with.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;smartphone-alarm-clock&#34;&gt;Smartphone Alarm Clock&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA; &#x9;&lt;div&gt;&#xA;     &lt;img src=&#34;https://d00k.net/img/knowledge/reusingtech01.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;A small smartphone with bright yellow sides, the screen shows 51% charge&#34;&gt;&#xA;     &lt;figcaption&gt;The Nokia 530&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;     &lt;hr&gt;&#xA; &#x9;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA; &lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first smartphone was this Nokia 530 running Windows Phone. I still have a huge soft spot for it, being small, light and bright it&amp;rsquo;s hard not to have a smile on your face using it. Windows Phone 8 is an OS still unbeaten in simplicity and function, it&amp;rsquo;s live tiles are a big favourite of mine. I&amp;rsquo;ve used this phone recently for college emails and calender, to keep college life physically separate. During this time I got into the habit of using the phone as alarm clock, and still do despite not using it for college stuff anymore. Some strict settings are in place to draw out the 1430mAh battery, including Airplane mode, constant battery saver mode, low brightness and turning off the phone while I&amp;rsquo;m awake. All this has given me roughly 40 days on a single charge which is quite nice. On android devices, I think deeper changes could be made in order to out even more draw battery life for an alarm clock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecovillages</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/ecovillage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 19:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/ecovillage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia describes an Ecovillage as &amp;ldquo;..a traditional or intentional community with the goal of becoming more socially, culturally, economically, and/or ecologically sustainable&amp;rdquo;, which perfectly describes the community in Cloughjordan EcoVillage. The village, which spreads over 67 acres, houses an amphitheatre,&#xA;a large &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloughjordancommunityfarm.ie/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;community farm&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.riotrye.ie/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;riot rye bakery&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoshostel.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;hostel&lt;/a&gt; and even a lovely &lt;a href=&#34;https://sheelaghnagig.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;bookstore&lt;/a&gt; that specialises in permaculture, sustainable living and activism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;village-characteristics&#34;&gt;Village Characteristics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://d00k.net/img/wiki/ecovillage04.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;Apartments behind a large town square&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cloughjordan Ecovillage has a large variety in housing, near the village entrance are a number of spacey apartment blocks surrounding the town square. As you go further in, there are mostly individual plots with houses of much variety in construction, most following an eco philosophy. There are many walking trails to houses off the main paths and roads. Trees encase these trails beautifully (see the images below for an example). Overall, nature is very much in control around these houses. There are no managed lawns or unfamiliar plants to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origami Designs</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/origami-designs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 18:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/origami-designs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;origami-modular-festive-tree&#34;&gt;Origami Modular Festive Tree&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://d00k.net/img/wiki/origami_designs_2.jpg&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;A green origami tree on a table&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Origami festive tree is a modular origami tree with little slots in the leaves to put whatever you want! It was designed as a modular, flat-packable festive tree that could be practical, allowing you to put different decorations or items in it. The design still needs some tweaking before I&amp;rsquo;m happy with posting instructions, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably get around to it soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beach Fossils</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/wiki/beachfossils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d00k.net/wiki/beachfossils/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beaches are filled with a vast number of different types of rocks and stones, but the ones that have always fascinated me are beach fossils. Fossil types can vary greatly based on your located, plants, shells and coral are all common types the can be found. Even chalk chunks are technically fossils!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my area, coral fossils are by far the most common. I&amp;rsquo;ve found ones of different shapes, sizes and quantities. In ancient times, coral reefs formed around active volcanos, which would have been likely for the seas around Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
