<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ipod on D00k</title>
    <link>https://d00k.net/tags/ipod/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ipod on D00k</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ie</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 15:12:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d00k.net/tags/ipod/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rockbox Theming</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 15:14:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, there have been many developments in the rockbox theming space. New ways of abstracting the theme tags rockbox uses to customise it&amp;rsquo;s UI have been created to give users even more functionality and better themes than ever before. However, a lot of these tricks are not well documented and involve being quite familiar with how rockbox theming works in order to extrapolate their construction. This guide intends to be a collection of these tricks, how to make them, as well as discussing some newer or rarely-used tags in rockbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Look Inside Themify</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/journal/inside_themify/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 15:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/journal/inside_themify/</guid>
      <description>After a few months of working on and off, I finally finished my next Rockbox theme: Themify. Themify does a lot of things I haven&amp;rsquo;t done yet in Rockbox, I really tried to push myself to create something cool and unique and I think the results definitely speak for themselves! This time, I decided to make a post here going over some of these features and generally looking into the code a bit more for those who are interested in that kind of thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Themify</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/ipod/themify/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 15:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/ipod/themify/</guid>
      <description>Themify is an advanced, user-customisable theme for Rockbox. Every on-screen element can be customised using Rockbox&amp;rsquo;s built in background and foreground colour settings. The theme features many adaptive elements, giving you a modern Rockbox experience like no other. This theme currently supports iPod Classic 5th, 6th and 7th generations.
The various screens of Themify Features ∘ Fully colour-customisable user interface. Background and Foreground colours can be set in the theme settings of Rockbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Spotify for Freer Pastures</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/journal/leaving-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 17:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/journal/leaving-spotify/</guid>
      <description>Over the past year, I&amp;rsquo;ve slowly worked on moving my listening activities away from Spotify and towards a setup where I have much more control over how I listen. As people will be checking out their Spotify Unwrapped, I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be a great time to talk about my thoughts on the platform and why I&amp;rsquo;m moving away from it.
Why leave? Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, Spotify is pretty great. Being able to listen to just about whatever I want, whenever I want and in decent quality is a great privilege.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>adwaitapod</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/projects/ipod/adwaitapod/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 14:45:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/projects/ipod/adwaitapod/</guid>
      <description>Adwaitapod is a modern and feature-rich theme for Rockbox. The theme uses the principles of Gnome&amp;rsquo;s Adwaita design language, and aims to be a complete and pleasing experience for users.The theme currently supports the iPod classic 5th, 6th and 7th gen.
Features ∘ Consistent interface with rounded corners. ∘ Custom Lockscreen when the Hold switch is on in the main menu, or when USB is connected. ∘ Radio Player skin with station icon support when using an FM Presets file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
