<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Knowledge on D00k</title>
    <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Knowledge on D00k</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ie</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 21:39:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d00k.net/knowledge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reusing Technology</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/reusingtech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 18:13:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/reusingtech/</guid>
      <description>Our world has a tech waste problem  There&amp;rsquo;s really no hiding the fact. Our world is built around fast fashion and fast tech, we buy and we throw out. Because of this, there&amp;rsquo;s loads of old, unused phones and other bits lying around the house that I&amp;rsquo;ve sought to utilise and solve problems with.
Smartphone Alarm Clock   The Nokia 530     My first smartphone was this Nokia 530 running Windows Phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecovillages</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ecovillage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 19:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ecovillage/</guid>
      <description>Wikipedia describes an Ecovillage as &amp;ldquo;..a traditional or intentional community with the goal of becoming more socially, culturally, economically, and/or ecologically sustainable&amp;rdquo;, which perfectly describes the community in Cloughjordan EcoVillage. The village, which spreads over 67 acres, houses an amphitheatre, a large community farm, the riot rye bakery, a hostel and even a lovely bookstore that specialises in permaculture, sustainable living and activism.
Village Characteristics      Cloughjordan Ecovillage has a large variety in housing, near the village entrance are a number of spacey apartment blocks surrounding the town square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origami</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/origami/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 18:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/origami/</guid>
      <description>Origami is the art of folding paper into various forms and objects. There are many different kinds of Origami other than traditional folding including modular designs like the Kusudamas, wet folding which allows creative sculpting, or even weaving with strip folding.
     The beautiful Origami Firework was the first design I ever made. Following a video tutorial, I struggled immensely to complete it but having no one to turn was an incredibly liberating experience as a teenager and the satisfaction of finishing it is something I still remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trichrome Technique</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/trichrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/trichrome/</guid>
      <description>Trichrome is a method of taking colour photography using different coloured filters (usually red, blue and green) to form a complete image. It was invented by Louis Ducos du Hauron in the late 19th century. It is most commonly used in black &amp;amp; white film photography to create atmospheric images, however the technique is usable with digital photography as well.
How does it work?  Shooting trichrome is quite simple, firstly you need lenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beach Fossils</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/beachfossils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/beachfossils/</guid>
      <description>Beaches are filled with a vast number of different types of rocks and stones, but the ones that have always fascinated me are beach fossils. Fossil types can vary greatly based on your located, plants, shells and coral are all common types the can be found. Even chalk chunks are technically fossils!
In my area, coral fossils are by far the most common. I&amp;rsquo;ve found ones of different shapes, sizes and quantities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
