<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rockbox on D00k</title>
    <link>https://d00k.net/guides/rockbox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rockbox on D00k</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ie</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 18:52:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d00k.net/guides/rockbox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 18:52:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>This has been a short guide of all the advanced rockbox theming things I know. Hopefully this helps people new to rockbox, and myself in the future when I return to making themes and inevitably forget everything. Thanks for reading!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Unused Functions</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/unused_functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 17:45:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/unused_functions/</guid>
      <description>∘ The xd tag - This might seem like an odd choice, the most used tag of all? But it actually has a different way using it that&amp;rsquo;s almost never used! The usual way is labelling images by a single letter, this is incredibly handy for writing stuff like battery indicators manually. However, the label can actual be anything you want! As written here on the Wiki:
%xd(label, &amp;lt;subimage number&amp;gt; [, offset])  Using the tag like this opens a huge amount of functionality, as well as making your code more readable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Overlay Images</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/overlay_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 17:37:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/overlay_images/</guid>
      <description>Drawing overlays in Rockbox is a neat trick to mask sections of the screen to create unique interface designs. While mostly used to create rounded corners on album art, the technique can actually be applied to any part of the screen.
How it works        Rockbox sees a specific RGB Value as transparent (another value it sees as the foreground colour) you can read more about it in the Notes of this section of the Wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Lockscreen</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/lockscreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 10:30:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/lockscreen/</guid>
      <description>The FreshOS Lockscreen by Yuuiko     There&amp;rsquo;s a rich history of Rockbox themes using the hold switch for additional functionality, however they followed the idea of showing extra info, or displaying album art. In comparison, Yuuiko uses the hold switch to unlock entirely unique screens in a way that enhances the capabilities of Rockbox.
How it works  The setup for lockscreens is surprisingly simple. It takes the same concept of background switching we&amp;rsquo;ve seen, but combines it with the function for the hold switch, allowing us to define what should be displayed when the switch is on and off!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Backdrop Switching</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/background_switching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 10:30:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/background_switching/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to making more advanced themes, switching backdrops is the door to most things. At it&amp;rsquo;s core, it essentially involves using Rockbox&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;current screen&amp;rdquo; tag to decide which backdrop gets displayed on which screen. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of all the available screens and their corresponding numbers:
No.| Screen 1 - Main Menu 2 - WPS (Music screen) 3 - Recording screen 4 - FM Radio screen 5 - Current Playlist screen 6 - Settings menus 7 - File browser 8 - Database browser 9 - Plugin browser 10 - Quickscreen 11 - Pitchscreen 12 - Setting chooser 13 - Playlist Catalogue Viewer 14 - Plugin 15 - Context menu 16 - System Info screen 17 - Time and Date Screen 18 - Bookmark browser 19 - Shortcuts menu 20 - Track Info screen 21 - USB Screen  Using the Function Usually this function is used in either of the following ways:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockbox Theming</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 15:14:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/ipod_modding/rockbox_theming/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, there have been many developments in the rockbox theming space. New ways of abstracting the theme tags rockbox uses to customise it&amp;rsquo;s UI have been created to give users even more functionality and better themes than ever before. However, a lot of these tricks are not well documented and involve being quite familiar with how rockbox theming works in order to extrapolate their construction. This guide intends to be a collection of these tricks, how to make them, as well as discussing some newer or rarely-used tags in rockbox.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
