<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Photography on D00k</title>
    <link>https://d00k.net/tags/photography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Photography on D00k</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ie</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 18:01:43 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d00k.net/tags/photography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bee Encyclopedia</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/bees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 18:01:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/bees/</guid>
      <description>Leaf Cutter Bee   Megachile (Delomegachile) willughbiella     The Leaf cutter bee is a near-threatened solitary bee species in Ireland. Identifiable by their unique characteristic of cutting and carrying leaves to use in their nests, which are usually in the ground or small cavities they find. There has only been 136 records of it since the 1800 in Ireland.
 ⬩ Irish Biodiversity Data Centre Profile.   ⬩ EOL Profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/about/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/about/setup/</guid>
      <description>A short breakdown of my setup, the hardware and software I use for creating and doing everyday work.
Hardware   Keychron C1 Keyboard    ∘ Lenovo Thinkpad E580 Laptop. - Going on 5 years old now, this was relatively cheap at the time for what it provided. Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded it with an SSD, more ram and so on. In 2021, I switched to using Fedora Linux from Windows and it&amp;rsquo;s been an incredibly smooth experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trichrome Technique</title>
      <link>https://d00k.net/knowledge/trichrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d00k.net/knowledge/trichrome/</guid>
      <description>Trichrome is a method of taking colour photography using different coloured filters (usually red, blue and green) to form a complete image. It was invented by Louis Ducos du Hauron in the late 19th century. It is most commonly used in black &amp;amp; white film photography to create atmospheric images, however the technique is usable with digital photography as well.
How does it work?  Shooting trichrome is quite simple, firstly you need lenses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
